<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>kubernetes on Nebrass Homepage</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/tags/kubernetes/</link><description>Recent content in kubernetes on Nebrass Homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.nebrass.fr/tags/kubernetes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Playing with Istio Service Mesh on Kubernetes</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-istio-service-mesh-on-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-istio-service-mesh-on-kubernetes/</guid><description>What is Istio? Google presents Istio as an open platform to connect, monitor, and secure microservices.
Istio is a service mesh implementation that provides many cloud-native capabilities like:
Traffic management: Service Discovery, Load balancing, Failure recovery, A/B testing, Canary releases, etc… Observability: Request Tracing, Metrics, Monitoring, Auditing, Logging, etc… Security: ACLs, Access control, Rate limiting, End-to-end authentication, etc… Istio delivers all these great features without any changes to the code of the microservices running with it on the same Kubernetes cluster.</description></item><item><title>Playing with Spring Boot on Kubernetes</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-spring-boot-on-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-spring-boot-on-kubernetes/</guid><description>I. Introduction In this tutorial I will show you how to write a small Spring Boot CRUD application and how to deploy it on Kubernetes.
Spring Boot is an innovative project that aims to make it easy to create Spring applications by simplifying the configuration and deployment actions through its convention over configuration based setup.
Kubernetes (commonly referred to as &amp;ldquo;K8s&amp;rdquo;) is an open-source system for automating deployment, scaling and management of containerized applications that was originally designed by Google and now maintained by the Cloud Native Computing Foundation.</description></item></channel></rss>