<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>other on Nebrass Homepage</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/categories/other/</link><description>Recent content in other on Nebrass Homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.nebrass.fr/categories/other/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Celebrating the 100 points in the Google Lighthouse Reports</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/celebrating-the-100-points-in-the-google-lighthouse-reports/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/celebrating-the-100-points-in-the-google-lighthouse-reports/</guid><description>In this post, I will share with you my experience starting from a disaster that occurred to my blog ☠️😢😭 until reaching the 100/100 performance score and get all Audits Validation Badges on Google Lighthouse 🏆🥇🎉🎊🎈💯/💯🥳
October 10th, I was writing a new post in my blog, in one of the previews, the site kept loading without giving any response. 😱😫😰😓😳🥵
My blog is based on the Wordpress CMS and hosted in an Ubuntu VPS by OVH since August 28th, 2015.</description></item><item><title>Istanbul Trip - June 2019</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/istanbul-trip-june-2019/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/istanbul-trip-june-2019/</guid><description>I was in Istanbul for nearly a week in a business trip. It was a very great trip : very rich cultural city, delicious food and very nice views 🤩
I had the chance to visit some attractions in the city:
Hagia Sophia Suleymaniye Mosque Grand Bazaar Spice Bazaar Blue Mosque Taksim Square https://www.flickr.com/photos/nebrass78/albums/72157709473573782</description></item><item><title>My talk for the Higher Colleges of Technology (HCT) - UAE</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/my-talk-for-the-higher-colleges-of-technology-hct-uae/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/my-talk-for-the-higher-colleges-of-technology-hct-uae/</guid><description>Tomorrow, I will give a talk for the Higher Colleges of Technology (HCT) titled &amp;ldquo;Introduction to the containerization security&amp;rdquo;. The talk is intended for the students of Computer Sciences students. It aims to introduce the Containerization and the benefits of Containers in matters of Web Applications Security.
The talk is organized by Mrs Samia Kouki, a former Computing Sciences assistant professor in ISG Tunis and a current assistant professor in HCT UAE.</description></item><item><title>Playing with Java Microservices on Kubernetes - ENSI 2018</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-java-microservices-on-kubernetes-ensi-2018/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-java-microservices-on-kubernetes-ensi-2018/</guid><description>I will be in the National School of Computing Sciences of Tunisia (ENSI Tunisia), from November 19th to November 24th 2018, to animate a 15 Hours workshop, about Microservices in Java and how to deploy them as Docker Containers to Kubernetes. The event is organized by Mrs Rim Drira.
The workshop content:
Part 1: The Monolithics Era Part 2: Coding the monolith Part 3: Microservices Era Part 4: Applying DDD to the code Part 5: Meeting &amp;amp; Implementing the µservices concerns and patterns Part 6: Building the standalone µservices Part 7: Packaging µservices in containers Part 8: Falling in ❤️ with container orchestrator: KUBERNETES 😍 Part 9: Applying the Kubernetes Style Many thanks for Mrs Rim Drira for the invitation and the event&amp;rsquo;s organization.</description></item><item><title>Workshop Report: ENSIT - May 2018</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/workshop-report-ensit-may-2018/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/workshop-report-ensit-may-2018/</guid><description>The workshop &amp;ldquo;Playing with Spring Boot and Angular&amp;rdquo; was held on May 4th 2018, at ENSIT**, Tunisia.**
The workshop content:
Introduction to Spring Boot Introduction to Spring Boot fundamentals Generating project using Spring Initializr Presentation of SpringBoot &amp;amp; autoconfigurations Creating CRUD application: Spring Data JPA + Spring Data REST Presentation of Spring Actuator Introduction to Angular TypeScript Fundamentals Angular Basics Template Syntax Components Services &amp;amp; Dependency Injection RxJS and Observables Communicating with the Server using the HttpClient Service The event was sponsored by onepoint.</description></item><item><title>Workshop Report: ISG Tunis - May 2018</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/workshop-report-isg-tunis-may-2018/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/workshop-report-isg-tunis-may-2018/</guid><description>The workshop &amp;ldquo;Playing with Spring Boot and Angular 5&amp;rdquo; was held on May 2nd 2018, at ISG Tunis, Tunisia.
The workshop content:
Introduction to Spring Boot Introduction to Spring Boot fundamentals Generating project using Spring Initializr Presentation of SpringBoot &amp;amp; autoconfigurations Creating CRUD application: Spring Data JPA + Spring Data REST Presentation of Spring Actuator Introduction to Angular 5 TypeScript Fundamentals Angular 5 Basics Template Syntax Components Services &amp;amp; Dependency Injection RxJS and Observables Communicating with the Server using the HttpClient Service Router The event was sponsored by onepoint.</description></item><item><title>Workshop Report: ENSI - April 2018</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/workshop-report-ensi-april-2018/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/workshop-report-ensi-april-2018/</guid><description>The workshop &amp;ldquo;Playing with Java Microservices with Docker&amp;rdquo; was held on Wednesday, 25th of April 2018, at the National School of Computer Sciences, in Mannouba, Tunisia.
Yeah ! We did it !! Many persons said it will be difficult to make an 8-hours workshop, but we made it !
The coffee breaks were sponsored by onepoint. The day ended with a giveaway of some Java Books to students.
It was great for everyone to see the great turn out and the plan is to have other Java Workshops soon, in many schools.</description></item><item><title>Playing with Java microservices with Docker - ENSI 2018</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-java-microservices-with-docker-ensi-2018/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-java-microservices-with-docker-ensi-2018/</guid><description>I will be in the National School of Computing Sciences of Tunisia (ENSI Tunisia), on April 25th 2018, to animate a full-day workshop, about Microservices in Java and how to deploy them as Docker Containers. The event is organized by the Open Source Software ENSI Club.
The workshop content:
Introduction to Enterprise Development &amp;amp; Architectures Introduction to Microservices Architectures Introduction to Spring Boot Introduction to Spring Boot fundamentals Generating project using Spring Initializr Presentation of SpringBoot &amp;amp; autoconfigurations Creating CRUD application: Spring Data JPA + Spring Data REST Presentation of Spring Actuator Introduction to the 12-Factors methodology Introduction to Microservices concerns &amp;amp; Spring Cloud Libraries Configuration Management Service Discovery Load Balancing API Gateway Service Security Centralized Loggin &amp;amp; Metrics Resilience &amp;amp; Fault Tolerance Packaging, Deployment &amp;amp; Scheduling Introduction to Docker Presentation of Containerization vs Virtualization Presentation of Docker&amp;rsquo;s terminology: Image; Container; Dockerfile; Docker-Machine Presentation of Docker-Compose, Docker-Swarm Presentation of Docker Hub &amp;amp; Continuous Delivery using Docker Requirements:</description></item><item><title>Comutec UTC Compiègne - October 2017</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/comutec-utc-compi%C3%A8gne-october-2017/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/comutec-utc-compi%C3%A8gne-october-2017/</guid><description>onepoint was present in the Comutec UTC 2017, which was held on October 19th, 2017, in Le Tigre space at Margny-lès-Compiègne.
For this event, we organized a small challenge for the UTC students: who can answer the questions that I have prepared ?
The questions are Java SE fundamentals related questions. The winner is the student that can have the highest correct answer.
The two winners got an Apple Watch 3rd generation !</description></item></channel></rss>