<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>netbeans on Nebrass Homepage</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/categories/netbeans/</link><description>Recent content in netbeans on Nebrass Homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.nebrass.fr/categories/netbeans/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My new book is here !!</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/my-new-book-is-here/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/my-new-book-is-here/</guid><description>Playing with Java Microservices on Kubernetes and OpenShift is here ! Today, November 24th 2018, I released my new book Playing with Java Microservices on Kubernetes and OpenShift!! Finally, after ten months of work, tests, POCs and many edition iterations, the newborn is here !
The book is edited and sold on the LeanPub platform 🤩
The book is sold mainly in two different offers:
The Book only The Book + one hour of training about Java Microservices and Kubernetes/OpenShift I have some ideas about making some other packages, I will post about them soon !</description></item><item><title>Workshop Report: ISG Tunis - November 2017</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/workshop-report-isg-tunis-november-2017/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/workshop-report-isg-tunis-november-2017/</guid><description>For the first time, since I started working, I animated a workshop on my lovely school, the Higher Institute of Management of Tunis, Tunisia. The greatest place that provided us with the love &amp;amp; the knowledge! The place where I coded my first lines of Java.
The event was organized by Aymen Delly, student &amp;amp; IT club president, and Mrs Nadia Yaacoubi, one of my greatest teachers.
The content of the workshop, to be presented from 8:00 to 13:00 :</description></item><item><title>Modern Software Development Bootcamp - Tunis</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/modern-software-development-bootcamp-tunis/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/modern-software-development-bootcamp-tunis/</guid><description>I participated today, the 6th of May, to the first edition of the Modern Software Development Bootcamp in Tunis, Tunisia.
The event was hosted by IntilaQ Center, El Ghazela Technopark, Tunisia.
Presentation of the Bootcamp:
The event is organized by Houssem Dellai, Microsoft MVP &amp;amp; Xamarin Lead Developer working at IntilaQ Center Tunisia &amp;amp; SOAT France. This event is dedicated to the computer engineering schools students, and aims to introduce them to the trendiest technologies of the market, such as Xamarin (C#/.</description></item><item><title>New version of "Playing with Spring Boot and Docker in NetBeans IDE"</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/new-version-of-playing-with-spring-boot-and-docker-in-netbeans-ide/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/new-version-of-playing-with-spring-boot-and-docker-in-netbeans-ide/</guid><description>This article is originally published April 13th, 2017 at JaxEnter website: Link
In this tutorial you will learn how to write a Java EE application using two of the trendiest technologies: Spring Boot and Docker in NetBeans IDE.
Spring Boot is an innovative project that aims to make it easy to create Spring applications by simplifying the configuration and deployment actions through its convention over configuration based setup. Docker is an open source project that automates the deployment of applications inside software containers.</description></item><item><title>NetBeans Day France 2017 - Grenoble</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/netbeans-day-france-2017-grenoble/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/netbeans-day-france-2017-grenoble/</guid><description>This year, the NetBeans France Community decided to make the NetBeans Day France 2017 in Grenoble City, at the 7th of February.
The event was hosted by Grenoble Informatics Laboratory, Grenoble Alpes University.
The planning of the event:
Welcome and overview of the day (Geertjan Wielenga, NetBeans) Session 1: Eclipse Vert.x &amp;amp; OpenShift (Clément Escoffier, Red Hat) Session 2: Enterprise JavaScript Development with Oracle JET (Geertjan Wielenga, NetBeans) Session 3: Playing with Spring Boot &amp;amp; Docker (Nebrass Lamouchi, Davidson SI) Session 4: JBoss Forge, WildFly and Java EE (Emmanuel Hugonnet, Red Hat) Some pictures from the event:</description></item><item><title>Playing with Spring Boot and Docker in NetBeans IDE</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-spring-boot-and-docker-in-netbeans-ide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-spring-boot-and-docker-in-netbeans-ide/</guid><description>In this tutorial you will learn how to write a Java EE application using two of the trendiest technologies: Spring Boot and Docker in NetBeans IDE.
Spring Boot is an innovative project that aims to make it easy to create Spring applications by simplifying the configuration and deployment actions through its convention over configuration based setup. Docker is an open source project that automates the deployment of applications inside software containers.</description></item><item><title>I'm now a NetBeans Dream Team Member!</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/im-now-a-netbeans-dream-team-member/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/im-now-a-netbeans-dream-team-member/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m excited to announce that I have been accepted to be a member of the NetBeans Dream Team, the team of highly skilled and passionate Java developers &amp;amp; NetBeans users. I&amp;rsquo;m so happy to be a member of such great team. It was one of my big dreams.
Presentation of the NetBeans Dream Team The NetBeans Dream Team is a community-driven group of highly skilled NetBeans users and contributors. They participate at NetBeans developer events, on mailing lists and developer forums, providing new, interesting and informative content as well as developing new and creative ways to promote NetBeans.</description></item></channel></rss>