<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>tutorials on Nebrass Homepage</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/categories/tutorials/</link><description>Recent content in tutorials on Nebrass Homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.nebrass.fr/categories/tutorials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Playing with Reactive Quarkus</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-reactive-quarkus/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-reactive-quarkus/</guid><description>Here we go again for a new post 😁 After publishing my Quarkus book last September, I got many requests about creating reactive applications with the Quarkus Framework.
Today, I will show you how to make a Reactive CRUD Application with the Quarkus Framework and backed by a PostgreSQL Database.
Building our the Reactive Quarkus Application The full source code is available on my Github.
We will generate our project using the code.</description></item><item><title>My upcoming book: Playing with Authentication and Authorization in OWASP Barbarus</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/my-upcoming-book-playing-with-authentication-and-authorization-in-owasp-barbarus/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/my-upcoming-book-playing-with-authentication-and-authorization-in-owasp-barbarus/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Playing with Azure Functions and Quarkus</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-azure-functions-and-quarkus/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-azure-functions-and-quarkus/</guid><description>Quarkus is one of the current trends of the Java ecosystem. I&amp;rsquo;m already in love with it. I&amp;rsquo;m using it along with Spring Boot, and when I choose, I choose Quarkus. 😁
This week, I was working on a Batch POC using Azure Functions and Azure Automation. So I thought it will be useful to share the exercise with you. 😁
What I want to do? I will be taking a small use case: I need a batch that will be invoked at some specific time or manually, checking all the available VMs and starting or shutting down all those that we choose.</description></item><item><title>Announcing Playing with Quarkus - Workshop Edition 🥳</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/announcing-playing-with-quarkus-workshop-edition/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/announcing-playing-with-quarkus-workshop-edition/</guid><description/></item><item><title>"Playing with Java Microservices with Quarkus and Kubernetes" is available in Early Access</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-java-microservices-with-quarkus-and-kubernetes-is-available-in-early-access/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-java-microservices-with-quarkus-and-kubernetes-is-available-in-early-access/</guid><description>Today is the big day 🥳🥳 My third book &amp;ldquo;Playing with Java Microservices with Quarkus and Kubernetes&amp;rdquo; is available in Early Access 🎉🎊🎈✨ Book cover
I started working on the book starting from June 😁 I spent nearly 5 months presenting the most interesting and powerful features of the Quarkus Framework. When I started the Proof-of-concept, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the idea of writing a book on Quarkus, I was just discovering.</description></item><item><title>Just finished the first four chapters..</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/just-finished-the-first-four-chapters../</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/just-finished-the-first-four-chapters../</guid><description>Today, I will not be sharing a tutorial or a review, I will share with you my new book news ! 🥳 I just finished typing the fourth chapter. These four chapters belong to the first part of the story: the MoNoLITHiC dedicated part 🤪 ..
What&amp;rsquo;s new ? In my previous book &amp;ldquo;Playing with Java Microservices on Kubernetes and OpenShift&amp;rdquo; there was a Docker-only chapter in the middle of the book.</description></item><item><title>My upcoming book: Playing with Java Microservices with Quarkus and Kubernetes</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/my-upcoming-book-playing-with-java-microservices-with-quarkus-and-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/my-upcoming-book-playing-with-java-microservices-with-quarkus-and-kubernetes/</guid><description>Today, I would like to share with you the title of my new book: Playing with Java Microservices with Quarkus and Kubernetes. I started working on it, since the July 2020.
Playing with Java Microservices with Quarkus Kubernetes will teach you how to build and design microservices using Java and the Red Hat Quarkus Framework.
This book covers topics related to creating Java microservices using Quarkus and deploying them to Kubernetes.</description></item><item><title>Playing with Reactive Spring Boot</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-reactive-spring-boot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-reactive-spring-boot/</guid><description>Reactive programming ! Wow ! What a fancy buzzy word ! I waited so much to write a blog post about this trend 😃 I was waiting for the landscape to be mature to made a one-shot tutorial 😁
Today, I will show you how to make a Reactive Spring Boot application, with a Reactive CRUDs using Spring Data Reactive Relational Database Connectivity (R2DBC) with PostgreSQL and for sure the famous Webflux.</description></item><item><title>Falling in love with Udacity ⚡️</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/falling-in-love-with-udacity-%EF%B8%8F/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/falling-in-love-with-udacity-%EF%B8%8F/</guid><description>Good ! This post has a conclusion into its title ! Udacity was the biggest discovery I&amp;rsquo;ve made during the COVID-19 lockdown 🤩 I was seeking for an interactive learning platform like DataCamp, where I finished all the trainings that I&amp;rsquo;m interested on. By the end of the February, I found Udacity while I was searching for some AI/ML intensive course.
Udacity Logo
⚠️ Disclaimer: This is not a marketing/referral post.</description></item><item><title>Playing with Spring Boot and Kafka on Azure Event Hub</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-spring-boot-and-kafka-on-azure-event-hub/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-spring-boot-and-kafka-on-azure-event-hub/</guid><description>In an enterprise level, it&amp;rsquo;s obvious for applications to be based on messaging for communication. This is done using a middleware between these applications as a Message Bus that enables them to work together.
One of the most used Messaging solutions is Apache Kafka: Kafka is an open-source stream-processing software platform developed by LinkedIn and donated to the Apache Software Foundation, written in Scala and Java. The project aims to provide a unified, high-throughput, low-latency platform for handling real-time data feeds.</description></item><item><title>Workshop Report: ENSI – January 2020</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/workshop-report-ensi-january-2020/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/workshop-report-ensi-january-2020/</guid><description>The workshop &amp;ldquo;Playing with Java Microservices on Kubernetes&amp;rdquo; was held from 02/01 to 04/01 - 2020, at the National School of Computer Sciences, in Manouba, Tunisia.
Great gift 😍
The workshop was done on 21 Hours of training about Java, Spring Boot, DDD, Docker, Kubernetes, Cloud Patterns, Azure AKS &amp;amp; Functions…
Some Github repositories used in the sessions:
Monolith Example Microservices Examples Speaker Deck The event was sponsored by Microsoft 😍🤩🥳 !</description></item><item><title>Playing with Java from 9 to 13</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-java-from-9-to-13/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-java-from-9-to-13/</guid><description>Since the release of Java SE 8, all the developers were under the charm of the Lambdas, Streams and even there those who fell in love with Nashorn for years (yes there are somewhere in this globe 😅).. With the crazy growth of the Enterprise Development context thru Spring Boot/Cloud, Docker, Kubernetes and the unlimited number of JS frameworks, the infinite patterns and styles of architectures, many developers lost the frequency of being up-to-date with the upstream 🤪</description></item><item><title>Playing with Java Microservices on Kubernetes - ENSI 2020</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-java-microservices-on-kubernetes-ensi-2020/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-java-microservices-on-kubernetes-ensi-2020/</guid><description>I will be in the National School of Computing Sciences of Tunisia (ENSI Tunisia), from the 2nd to 4th January 2020, to animate a 20 Hours workshop, about Microservices in Java and how to deploy them as Docker Containers to Kubernetes. The event is organized by Mrs Rim Drira.
The workshop content:
Part 1: The Monolithics Era Part 2: Coding the monolith Part 3: Microservices Era Part 4: Applying DDD to the code Part 5: Meeting &amp;amp; Implementing the µservices concerns and patterns Part 6: Building the standalone µservices Part 7: Packaging µservices in containers Part 8: Falling in 🥰 with container orchestrator: KUBERNETES 😍 Part 9: Applying the Kubernetes Style Part 10: Meeting Azure ☁️ Part X: What ’s next ?</description></item><item><title>Playing with CQRS and Event Sourcing in Spring Boot and Axon</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-cqrs-and-event-sourcing-in-spring-boot-and-axon/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-cqrs-and-event-sourcing-in-spring-boot-and-axon/</guid><description>The Microservices Architecture World, we can meet many concepts and patterns, like the Centralized Configuration, Circuit Breaker, Service Registry and Discovery, etc.. Two of these patterns are the CQRS and the Event Sourcing patterns, coming from the Domain Driven Design planet 🌏 In the most of the use-cases, these two patterns are sold together 😁 in this new tutorial, we will discover what does each one ? why they are usually used together ?</description></item><item><title>Playing with the JVM inside Docker Containers</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-the-jvm-inside-docker-containers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-the-jvm-inside-docker-containers/</guid><description>Nowadays, the most of the Java microservices and even many Java application are packaged and deployed as Docker containers. Everyone is enjoying (I hope 😆) the Docker experience, compared to the traditional VMs. But, the Docker containerization will not come alone.. nothing is autonomous 😁 So, there are many concerns to take into consideration while containerizing Java applications, like playing with the JVM.
The Docker racing was accelerated by the presence of Kubernetes in the market, which is coming with an amazing set of great features.</description></item><item><title>Playing with Serverless in Kubernetes with Knative</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-serverless-in-kubernetes-with-knative/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-serverless-in-kubernetes-with-knative/</guid><description>The serverless architecture became one of the most buzzy words nowadays. Almost all the cloud providers have a Serverless platforms in their catalogues:
Microsoft Azure Functions Amazon Web Services Lambda Google Cloud Functions IBM Cloud Functions Oracle Functions In an other world, there are many solutions to have a Serverless Runtime into Kubernetes, which is the most popular (and the most wonderful) container orchestrator in the market. These solutions are so helpful especially if you need portability for your functions.</description></item><item><title>Playing with Serverless Architecture</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-serverless-architecture/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-serverless-architecture/</guid><description>In some previous articles, I was writing about the Azure Functions, which is the Microsoft Serverless solutions. After joining Microsoft, I got the chance to work on this great product for many business cases and I found it was really great 🥳
Recently, one of my Facebook friends asked me to write a blog post about what is Serverless architecture ? 🤔 what is for ? 🤔 and especially, what are the scenarios that are not suitable for Serverless ?</description></item><item><title>Playing with Spring Cloud in Azure Functions</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-spring-cloud-in-azure-functions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-spring-cloud-in-azure-functions/</guid><description>In this tutorial, we will be experimenting a new use case of the great Azure Functions service 😁 one of my favorite products in Azure.
In this tutorial, we will bring the powerful features of the Spring Framework to our Azure Functions Java projects. After this tutorial, creating a new Azure Functions Java based on business logic that you already have in your Spring Boot Application will be a very easy game.</description></item><item><title>Playing with Java in Azure Functions - New Release</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-java-in-azure-functions-new-release/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-java-in-azure-functions-new-release/</guid><description>In one of the previous posts, I introduced the Azure Functions Java. I felt that I need to write a dedicated tutorial to this great Azure Serverless service 😁
In this post, I will be covering many concepts in deep:
Triggers and bindings Events and messaging Deployments &amp;amp; Consumptions Monitoring Generating the hello-world project We will scaffold a Java-based Azure Function project using Maven Archetypes, using this command:</description></item><item><title>Playing with Azure Monitor services and Spring Boot</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-azure-monitor-services-and-spring-boot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-azure-monitor-services-and-spring-boot/</guid><description>In enterprise application, performance is major requirement of success. Especially for applications where slowness will have a direct detrimental impact on business productivity, profits and even the brand itself, like trading platforms and e-commerces.
If a trading platform loads slowly or experiences errors, it will translate into loss of business, and losses can be extremely high, and the customer might end up switching to another competitor.
In this context comes the Application Performance Management (APM).</description></item><item><title>Playing with OpenShift 4 locally</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-openshift-4-locally/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-openshift-4-locally/</guid><description>January 2018, Red Hat acquired CoreOS for 250 million dollars 🤩. CoreOS was one of the leading companies of Linux &amp;amp; Containers market with their wide offer of products:
CoreOS Tectonic: container application platform based on Kubernetes. CoreOS Container Linux: lightweight Linux distribution designed to run containerized applications. CoreOS Operators Framework: an open source toolkit designed to manage Kubernetes native applications. CoreOS Quay: a container registry for building, storing, and distributing your private containers.</description></item><item><title>Playing with Java under the shield of SonarQube</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-java-under-the-shield-of-sonarqube/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-java-under-the-shield-of-sonarqube/</guid><description>Introduction We.. developers.. we spend all our time writing code (and drinking coffee).. but we rarely care about the code quality.. until we get some pressure from a reviewer or from some quality scanner tool.. and as every field in the Java ecosystem, we have many choices when we come to choose a Quality Scanner tool: FindBugs, CheckStyle, PMD and of course the GREATEST SonarQube 😍
I fully worked with SonarQube since January 2014, during my M.</description></item><item><title>Big up! My book is FREE now !!</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/big-up-my-book-is-free-now/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/big-up-my-book-is-free-now/</guid><description>To celebrate the Groundbreaker Award and Oracle Code New York, my book &amp;ldquo;Playing with Java Microservices on Kubernetes and OpenShift&amp;rdquo; will be FREE forever !
This is a gift is for the community that voted for me and helped me to achieve this great award ! 🤩
The book is available on the Leanpub website:
Thank you so much for voting for me !! 🥳</description></item><item><title>Discovering Machine Learning ?!</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/discovering-machine-learning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/discovering-machine-learning/</guid><description>Some days ago, I got an idea to make a personal project about &amp;ldquo;Connected Devices&amp;rdquo;. This idea led me to discover some Artificial Intelligence and especially Machine Learning.
The first thing that I did: I started seeking for a good course in many websites: edx, coursera and udemy.. These are the most popular sites of elearning that I am usually referencing to when I want to attack new technology or any CS field.</description></item><item><title>Playing with Istio Service Mesh on Kubernetes</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-istio-service-mesh-on-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-istio-service-mesh-on-kubernetes/</guid><description>What is Istio? Google presents Istio as an open platform to connect, monitor, and secure microservices.
Istio is a service mesh implementation that provides many cloud-native capabilities like:
Traffic management: Service Discovery, Load balancing, Failure recovery, A/B testing, Canary releases, etc… Observability: Request Tracing, Metrics, Monitoring, Auditing, Logging, etc… Security: ACLs, Access control, Rate limiting, End-to-end authentication, etc… Istio delivers all these great features without any changes to the code of the microservices running with it on the same Kubernetes cluster.</description></item><item><title>New book update #1</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/new-book-update-#1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/new-book-update-#1/</guid><description>I just updated my book « Playing with Java Microservices with Kubernetes and OpenShift » 😃
The release changelog:
Fixed some typos 🙈 I just finished writing the Chapter 14: Getting started with OpenShift 👌 I started writing the Chapter 15: The OpenShift style 🎶 I started working on Istio Tutorial that will be the first bonus chapter in the book ⚡️⚡️ I will be covering more and more subjects soon 😁</description></item><item><title>My new book is here !!</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/my-new-book-is-here/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/my-new-book-is-here/</guid><description>Playing with Java Microservices on Kubernetes and OpenShift is here ! Today, November 24th 2018, I released my new book Playing with Java Microservices on Kubernetes and OpenShift!! Finally, after ten months of work, tests, POCs and many edition iterations, the newborn is here !
The book is edited and sold on the LeanPub platform 🤩
The book is sold mainly in two different offers:
The Book only The Book + one hour of training about Java Microservices and Kubernetes/OpenShift I have some ideas about making some other packages, I will post about them soon !</description></item><item><title>Playing with Spring Boot on Kubernetes</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-spring-boot-on-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-spring-boot-on-kubernetes/</guid><description>I. Introduction In this tutorial I will show you how to write a small Spring Boot CRUD application and how to deploy it on Kubernetes.
Spring Boot is an innovative project that aims to make it easy to create Spring applications by simplifying the configuration and deployment actions through its convention over configuration based setup.
Kubernetes (commonly referred to as &amp;ldquo;K8s&amp;quot;) is an open-source system for automating deployment, scaling and management of containerized applications that was originally designed by Google and now maintained by the Cloud Native Computing Foundation.</description></item><item><title>My upcoming book: Playing with Java Microservices on Kubernetes and OpenShift</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/my-upcoming-book-playing-with-java-microservices-on-kubernetes-and-openshift/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/my-upcoming-book-playing-with-java-microservices-on-kubernetes-and-openshift/</guid><description>Today, I would like to share with you the title of my new book: Playing with Java Microservices on Kubernetes and OpenShift.
I started working on it, since the January 2018.
Playing with Java Microservices on Kubernetes and OpenShift will teach you how to build and design microservices using Java and the Spring platform.
This book covers topics related to creating Java microservices and deploy them to Kubernetes and OpenShift.</description></item><item><title>New version of "Playing with Spring Boot and Docker in NetBeans IDE"</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/new-version-of-playing-with-spring-boot-and-docker-in-netbeans-ide/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/new-version-of-playing-with-spring-boot-and-docker-in-netbeans-ide/</guid><description>This article is originally published April 13th, 2017 at JaxEnter website: Link
In this tutorial you will learn how to write a Java EE application using two of the trendiest technologies: Spring Boot and Docker in NetBeans IDE.
Spring Boot is an innovative project that aims to make it easy to create Spring applications by simplifying the configuration and deployment actions through its convention over configuration based setup. Docker is an open source project that automates the deployment of applications inside software containers.</description></item><item><title>Playing with Spring Boot and Docker in NetBeans IDE</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-spring-boot-and-docker-in-netbeans-ide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-spring-boot-and-docker-in-netbeans-ide/</guid><description>In this tutorial you will learn how to write a Java EE application using two of the trendiest technologies: Spring Boot and Docker in NetBeans IDE.
Spring Boot is an innovative project that aims to make it easy to create Spring applications by simplifying the configuration and deployment actions through its convention over configuration based setup. Docker is an open source project that automates the deployment of applications inside software containers.</description></item><item><title>Talk Report: From JavaEE to AngularJS - Video &amp; Slides</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/talk-report-from-javaee-to-angularjs-video-slides/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/talk-report-from-javaee-to-angularjs-video-slides/</guid><description>NetBeans Day Paris, for the first time in France, held on the October 16th, 2015. It was a very nice opportunity to meet NetBeans users and developers in Paris Area.
My presentation is a live coding session showing how to make a sample app from scratch on NetBeans, using many trendy technologies and APIs:
IDE: NetBeans 8.0.2 Server: Payara Server 4.1.153 Backend: Java EE 7 [JPA 2.1, EJB 3.2, CDI 1.</description></item></channel></rss>