<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>courses on Nebrass Homepage</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/categories/courses/</link><description>Recent content in courses on Nebrass Homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.nebrass.fr/categories/courses/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Workshop Report: ENSI – January 2020</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/workshop-report-ensi-january-2020/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/workshop-report-ensi-january-2020/</guid><description>The workshop &amp;ldquo;Playing with Java Microservices on Kubernetes&amp;rdquo; was held from 02/01 to 04/01 - 2020, at the National School of Computer Sciences, in Manouba, Tunisia.
Great gift 😍
The workshop was done on 21 Hours of training about Java, Spring Boot, DDD, Docker, Kubernetes, Cloud Patterns, Azure AKS &amp;amp; Functions…
Some Github repositories used in the sessions:
Monolith Example Microservices Examples Speaker Deck The event was sponsored by Microsoft 😍🤩🥳 !</description></item><item><title>Big up! My book is FREE now !!</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/big-up-my-book-is-free-now/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/big-up-my-book-is-free-now/</guid><description>To celebrate the Groundbreaker Award and Oracle Code New York, my book &amp;ldquo;Playing with Java Microservices on Kubernetes and OpenShift&amp;rdquo; will be FREE forever !
This is a gift is for the community that voted for me and helped me to achieve this great award ! 🤩
The book is available on the Leanpub website:
Thank you so much for voting for me !! 🥳</description></item><item><title>Discovering Machine Learning ?!</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/discovering-machine-learning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/discovering-machine-learning/</guid><description>Some days ago, I got an idea to make a personal project about &amp;ldquo;Connected Devices&amp;rdquo;. This idea led me to discover some Artificial Intelligence and especially Machine Learning.
The first thing that I did: I started seeking for a good course in many websites: edx, coursera and udemy.. These are the most popular sites of elearning that I am usually referencing to when I want to attack new technology or any CS field.</description></item><item><title>My new book is here !!</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/my-new-book-is-here/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/my-new-book-is-here/</guid><description>Playing with Java Microservices on Kubernetes and OpenShift is here ! Today, November 24th 2018, I released my new book Playing with Java Microservices on Kubernetes and OpenShift!! Finally, after ten months of work, tests, POCs and many edition iterations, the newborn is here !
The book is edited and sold on the LeanPub platform 🤩
The book is sold mainly in two different offers:
The Book only The Book + one hour of training about Java Microservices and Kubernetes/OpenShift I have some ideas about making some other packages, I will post about them soon !</description></item><item><title>OWASP Day - Capgemini Nantes</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/owasp-day-capgemini-nantes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/owasp-day-capgemini-nantes/</guid><description>I had the honour to be the first guest of the NTIC Community, of Capgemini Nantes, to animate a &amp;ldquo;Two-Talks Event&amp;rdquo;, a new action made by the managers of NTIC Community to boost the brainstorming and motivation of the IT Managers and Technical Teams.
The subject of the first edition was &amp;ldquo;Security for Managers and Technicals&amp;rdquo;.
My talks:
Security for IT Managers : 14:30 - 15:30 Presentation of the OWASP Barbarus : 16:00 - 17:00 My Presentations:</description></item><item><title>Modern Software Development Bootcamp - Tunis</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/modern-software-development-bootcamp-tunis/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/modern-software-development-bootcamp-tunis/</guid><description>I participated today, the 6th of May, to the first edition of the Modern Software Development Bootcamp in Tunis, Tunisia.
The event was hosted by IntilaQ Center, El Ghazela Technopark, Tunisia.
Presentation of the Bootcamp:
The event is organized by Houssem Dellai, Microsoft MVP &amp;amp; Xamarin Lead Developer working at IntilaQ Center Tunisia &amp;amp; SOAT France. This event is dedicated to the computer engineering schools students, and aims to introduce them to the trendiest technologies of the market, such as Xamarin (C#/.</description></item><item><title>Free self-paced courses to learn Docker</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/free-self-paced-courses-to-learn-docker/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/free-self-paced-courses-to-learn-docker/</guid><description>This week, I tried the &amp;ldquo;Self Paced Online&amp;rdquo; courses provided by the Docker Community. These courses were built by many mentors &amp;amp; Docker experts, covering many basic &amp;amp; advanced Docker concepts.
The offered courses:
Developer - Beginner Linux Containers
This tutorial will guide you through the steps involved in setting up your computer, running your first containers, deploying a web application with Docker and running a multi-container voting app with Docker Compose.</description></item></channel></rss>