<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>workshops on Nebrass Homepage</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/categories/workshops/</link><description>Recent content in workshops on Nebrass Homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.nebrass.fr/categories/workshops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Workshop Report: ENSI – January 2020</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/workshop-report-ensi-january-2020/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/workshop-report-ensi-january-2020/</guid><description>The workshop &amp;ldquo;Playing with Java Microservices on Kubernetes&amp;rdquo; was held from 02/01 to 04/01 - 2020, at the National School of Computer Sciences, in Manouba, Tunisia.
Great gift 😍
The workshop was done on 21 Hours of training about Java, Spring Boot, DDD, Docker, Kubernetes, Cloud Patterns, Azure AKS &amp;amp; Functions…
Some Github repositories used in the sessions:
Monolith Example Microservices Examples Speaker Deck The event was sponsored by Microsoft 😍🤩🥳 !</description></item><item><title>Playing with Java Microservices on Kubernetes - ENSI 2020</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-java-microservices-on-kubernetes-ensi-2020/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-java-microservices-on-kubernetes-ensi-2020/</guid><description>I will be in the National School of Computing Sciences of Tunisia (ENSI Tunisia), from the 2nd to 4th January 2020, to animate a 20 Hours workshop, about Microservices in Java and how to deploy them as Docker Containers to Kubernetes. The event is organized by Mrs Rim Drira.
The workshop content:
Part 1: The Monolithics Era Part 2: Coding the monolith Part 3: Microservices Era Part 4: Applying DDD to the code Part 5: Meeting &amp;amp; Implementing the µservices concerns and patterns Part 6: Building the standalone µservices Part 7: Packaging µservices in containers Part 8: Falling in 🥰 with container orchestrator: KUBERNETES 😍 Part 9: Applying the Kubernetes Style Part 10: Meeting Azure ☁️ Part X: What ’s next ?</description></item><item><title>My new book is here !!</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/my-new-book-is-here/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/my-new-book-is-here/</guid><description>Playing with Java Microservices on Kubernetes and OpenShift is here ! Today, November 24th 2018, I released my new book Playing with Java Microservices on Kubernetes and OpenShift!! Finally, after ten months of work, tests, POCs and many edition iterations, the newborn is here !
The book is edited and sold on the LeanPub platform 🤩
The book is sold mainly in two different offers:
The Book only The Book + one hour of training about Java Microservices and Kubernetes/OpenShift I have some ideas about making some other packages, I will post about them soon !</description></item><item><title>Workshop Report: ENSI – November 2018</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/workshop-report-ensi-november-2018/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/workshop-report-ensi-november-2018/</guid><description>The workshop &amp;ldquo;Playing with Java Microservices on Kubernetes&amp;rdquo; was held from 19/11 to 24/11, at the National School of Computer Sciences, in Mannouba, Tunisia.
The workshop was done on 18 Hours of training about Java, Spring Boot, DDD, Docker, Kubernetes, Cloud Patterns, CI/CD&amp;hellip;
Some Github repositories used in the sessions:
Monolith Example Microservices Examples We got even a special guest, my techno-mate Houssem Dellai, the great Microsoft MVP, that presented, thru a 3 Hours session, Docker &amp;amp; Kubernetes and the CI/CD lifecycles with a great demo of Azure DevOps for the students of ENSI Tunisia.</description></item><item><title>Meetup Report: Architecture in the Cloud Era</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/meetup-report-architecture-in-the-cloud-era/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/meetup-report-architecture-in-the-cloud-era/</guid><description>We organized, at Onepoint, our first Architecture Meetup, the 19th of July, in our beautiful headquarters in Trocadéro, Paris.
Our first edition&amp;rsquo;s guest:
Aymen El Amri : the founder of eralabs a consulting and training company and, a community hub. He help companies build and learn how to build modern and cloud native applications.
He&amp;rsquo;s written tech books like Painless Docker and founded online communities like DevOpsLinks and Kaptain.</description></item><item><title>First Architecture MeetUp @Onepoint - July 2018</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/first-architecture-meetup-onepoint-july-2018/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/first-architecture-meetup-onepoint-july-2018/</guid><description>Le jeudi 19 juillet à l&amp;rsquo;Atelier, la communauté Architecture exposera des REXs, des démos, des workshops avec un invité mondialement reconnu sur le DevOps, le CloudNative et les architectures modernes : Aymen El Amri.
Notre special guest :
Aymen El Amri - Meilleures pratiques de réalisation d&amp;rsquo;applications Cloud Native
Aymen El Amri a été reconnu par TechBeacon comme l&amp;rsquo;un des Top 100 leaders, praticiens, experts de DevOps à suivre. Il est le fondateur d&amp;rsquo;eralabs, une société de conseil et de formation et un Community-Hub.</description></item><item><title>Workshop Report: ENSIT - May 2018</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/workshop-report-ensit-may-2018/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/workshop-report-ensit-may-2018/</guid><description>The workshop &amp;ldquo;Playing with Spring Boot and Angular&amp;rdquo; was held on May 4th 2018, at ENSIT**, Tunisia.**
The workshop content:
Introduction to Spring Boot Introduction to Spring Boot fundamentals Generating project using Spring Initializr Presentation of SpringBoot &amp;amp; autoconfigurations Creating CRUD application: Spring Data JPA + Spring Data REST Presentation of Spring Actuator Introduction to Angular TypeScript Fundamentals Angular Basics Template Syntax Components Services &amp;amp; Dependency Injection RxJS and Observables Communicating with the Server using the HttpClient Service The event was sponsored by onepoint.</description></item><item><title>Workshop Report: IntilaQ - May 2018</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/workshop-report-intilaq-may-2018/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/workshop-report-intilaq-may-2018/</guid><description>The workshop &amp;ldquo;Playing with Java Microservices with Kubernetes and OpenShift&amp;rdquo; was held on May 3rd 2018, at IntilaQ Center, El Ghazela Technopark, Tunisia.
The content of the workshop was :
Introduction to Microservices Architectures Introduction to the 12-Factors methodology Introduction to Microservices concerns &amp;amp; Spring Cloud Libraries Configuration Management Service Discovery Load Balancing API Gateway Service Security Centralized Logging &amp;amp; Metrics Resilience &amp;amp; Fault Tolerance Packaging, Deployment &amp;amp; Scheduling Introduction to Kubernetes The event was co-organized by Houssem Dellai and sponsored by onepoint.</description></item><item><title>Playing with Spring Boot and Angular 5 - ISG Tunis 2018</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-spring-boot-and-angular-5-isg-tunis-2018/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/playing-with-spring-boot-and-angular-5-isg-tunis-2018/</guid><description>I will animate a workshop in my school, ISG Tunis, Tunisia, on the May 2nd, 2018. The workshop will be about Spring Boot &amp;amp; Angular 5 development.
The workshop content:
Introduction to Spring Boot Introduction to Spring Boot fundamentals Generating project using Spring Initializr Presentation of SpringBoot &amp;amp; autoconfigurations Creating CRUD application: Spring Data JPA + Spring Data REST Presentation of Spring Actuator Introduction to Angular 5 TypeScript Fundamentals Angular 5 Basics Template Syntax Components Services &amp;amp; Dependency Injection RxJS and Observables Communicating with the Server using the HttpClient Service Router Requirements:</description></item><item><title>Incoming training: Playing with Spring Boot on Kubernetes Bootcamp</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/incoming-training-playing-with-spring-boot-on-kubernetes-bootcamp/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/incoming-training-playing-with-spring-boot-on-kubernetes-bootcamp/</guid><description>Content and details to be defined soon&amp;hellip;
If you have any special requests, please feel free to contact me by mail.</description></item><item><title>Workshop Report: ISG Tunis - November 2017</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/workshop-report-isg-tunis-november-2017/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/workshop-report-isg-tunis-november-2017/</guid><description>For the first time, since I started working, I animated a workshop on my lovely school, the Higher Institute of Management of Tunis, Tunisia. The greatest place that provided us with the love &amp;amp; the knowledge! The place where I coded my first lines of Java.
The event was organized by Aymen Delly, student &amp;amp; IT club president, and Mrs Nadia Yaacoubi, one of my greatest teachers.
The content of the workshop, to be presented from 8:00 to 13:00 :</description></item><item><title>Announcement: Summer School Tunisia 2017</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/announcement-summer-school-tunisia-2017/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/announcement-summer-school-tunisia-2017/</guid><description>Summer School is a unique opportunity to learn about developing web and mobile applications that meets the requirements of good design, high scalability and faster integration/deployment.
Two parallel tracks will run together and participants have to choose on the two.
The first track will be around Java EE enviroment.
Nabrass Lamouchi - Team Leader at Société Générale &amp;amp; Netbeans Dream Team member
Day 1
Intro to Enterprise Development Intro to Java EE specifications Intro to Java 8 Intro to Spring Boot Legacy and SOA trendies Diving into Microservices architecture Getting into Agility for Microservices Development Day 2</description></item><item><title>OWASP Day - Capgemini Nantes</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/owasp-day-capgemini-nantes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/owasp-day-capgemini-nantes/</guid><description>I had the honour to be the first guest of the NTIC Community, of Capgemini Nantes, to animate a &amp;ldquo;Two-Talks Event&amp;rdquo;, a new action made by the managers of NTIC Community to boost the brainstorming and motivation of the IT Managers and Technical Teams.
The subject of the first edition was &amp;ldquo;Security for Managers and Technicals&amp;rdquo;.
My talks:
Security for IT Managers : 14:30 - 15:30 Presentation of the OWASP Barbarus : 16:00 - 17:00 My Presentations:</description></item><item><title>NetBeans Day France 2017 - Grenoble</title><link>https://blog.nebrass.fr/netbeans-day-france-2017-grenoble/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nebrass.fr/netbeans-day-france-2017-grenoble/</guid><description>This year, the NetBeans France Community decided to make the NetBeans Day France 2017 in Grenoble City, at the 7th of February.
The event was hosted by Grenoble Informatics Laboratory, Grenoble Alpes University.
The planning of the event:
Welcome and overview of the day (Geertjan Wielenga, NetBeans) Session 1: Eclipse Vert.x &amp;amp; OpenShift (Clément Escoffier, Red Hat) Session 2: Enterprise JavaScript Development with Oracle JET (Geertjan Wielenga, NetBeans) Session 3: Playing with Spring Boot &amp;amp; Docker (Nebrass Lamouchi, Davidson SI) Session 4: JBoss Forge, WildFly and Java EE (Emmanuel Hugonnet, Red Hat) Some pictures from the event:</description></item></channel></rss>